<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Design</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/15/Design/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/15/Design/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/SJAkEHN.jpg"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/71ThOmN.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/xJOi6CH.png"></p><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9UI7U-O7e-E" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gx1kp9MHw1s" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Design</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Visual &amp; Video</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tac Pro</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Tac-Pro/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Tac-Pro/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>DESIGNED FOR E-SPORTS FPS PLAYER</em></p><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B28RtBR7ZrM" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p><a href="https://github.com/SplashCrBy/tacpro">Github Link</a></p><h3 id="the-Background-of-our-team"><a href="#the-Background-of-our-team" class="headerlink" title="the Background of our team"></a>the Background of our team</h3><p>Our team was made of three people who not only were designers but also players enjoyed playing video games a lot. As a result, they wanted to figure out some problems encountered by video game players and solve them with their own hands.</p><p>My Role: UI&#x2F;UX designer &amp; Web Developer</p><p>Team members: Ming Xie, Sizhao Li, Yifei Xie</p><p>Tools: Illustrator, Photoshop, HTML&#x2F;CSS&#x2F;JS</p><p>Website: <a href="https://jasonxieyf.github.io/tacpro/">https://jasonxieyf.github.io/tacpro/</a>  </p><p>Account &amp; password for testing:</p><p>tacpro</p><p>1234</p><h3 id="THEME"><a href="#THEME" class="headerlink" title="THEME"></a>THEME</h3><p>The topic our group wants to pick is the one about recreation so we decide to observe people’s behavior when they playing video games to summarize their needs during the playing progress. The samples we choose are our friends as we are able to have a direct communication with them and retrieve feedback immediately through close observation. Because video game is a very common way of recreation and players may or may not have similar needs according to the type of game they prefer, so we think this topic is very interesting and worth to be further explored.</p><h3 id="PROBLEM"><a href="#PROBLEM" class="headerlink" title="PROBLEM"></a>PROBLEM</h3><p>According to the observation of gameplay of several college students, we found out that the most popular games among them were first personal shooting game and Pokemon. Therefore, we summarized their needs through reviewing the video we recorded when they were playing.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/m9UtRDR.jpg"></p><ol><li><p>Players need a more straightforward interface&#x2F;database which can systematically display information and precompute some basic information for players.</p></li><li><p>Players need some complementary well designed tools rather than some general ones to relieve their stresses.  </p></li><li><p>Players need intuitive ways of interaction to diminish unnecessary time wasting on thinking and increase the precision of their control.</p></li><li><p>Players need a social system to communicate with people of the same type of hobbies.</p></li><li><p>Players need a portable platform that allow them to not only backup their data but also study the potential possibilities of the game whenever and wherever possible.</p></li></ol><p><strong>CONCLUSION: PEOPLE SHOULD HAVE A WAY OF ACQUIRING INFORMATION MORE EFFICIENTLY AND ACCURATELY.</strong></p><h2 id="STORY-BOARD-AND-PROTOTYPING"><a href="#STORY-BOARD-AND-PROTOTYPING" class="headerlink" title="STORY BOARD AND PROTOTYPING"></a>STORY BOARD AND PROTOTYPING</h2><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ggWTLG3.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/C39KI9a.png"></p><blockquote><p>The main problems I identify in their prototypes are that though the main functions are relatively clear for users, there is no navigation system for them to switch between functions. The flow of these prototypes may not be very ideally smooth due to lacking such functions. Some of the functions are really great ideas, but may need a better design of the flows and layouts. Also, there is no error prevention, diagozation, help or documentation for now. These parts are essential for users to get started and maintain an enjoyable experience. ——— Feedbacks from other students</p></blockquote><p>According to the feedbacks we receive from the other group and our preference, we decide to focus on our first prototype because its flow is relatively more clear to be understood by beginners and we do not find any similar products on the market right now.  Therefore, we are going to remake the App based on the other group’s opinions to create a fantastic product.  </p><ul><li><p>Clear indication&#x2F;icons on map tagging</p><ul><li>The tags we first decided to let users use were their avatars so that they could distinguish the messages easily during the game. However, the feedback suggests that they are not intuitive enough when people are playing intense games and we should use some simpler symbols instead. As a result, we plan to use icons with solid colors to represent different team members so that   they can quickly understand the meaning when those icons show up on their screens. Furthermore, we will add more icons even DIY functions for user to customize their own icons for convenience.</li></ul></li><li><p>A front page for beginner guidance and troubleshooting function</p><ul><li>The members from other group point out that our Apps are lack of tutorial and error prevention mechanism which may lead to some unexpected issues such as misuse of set of icons. What’s more, even though the target users may already know what is the App for, we still need some basic guidance to help users to get started as soon as possible. Correspondly, we are going to add some texts and arrows at the menu page when the App is opened for the first time to tell users the flow of the App.</li></ul></li><li><p>Add navigation bar for quick access</p><ul><li>The members from other group points out that we don’t have navigation bar or similar functions. So when users want to go back to home page for example, they need to do that step by step, which is very inefficient. So we may need to add a navigation bar on the bottom to lead users to go the the pages they want to go. Then contents in the navigation bar should include “home”, “current game” ,”account”. More detail information should be discussed.</li></ul></li><li><p>Allow user made custom map for “other games”</p><ul><li>One of the feedbacks is that there are not enough games supported. We don’t have the resource to make the map for every game. However we may be able to create a custom map editor to allow user to load their own map for whatever game they want to use. They may also use this function to navigate inside a known but complex environment. The use of this map can be extended to real life.</li></ul></li><li><p>Allow import of friend lists from other platforms</p><ul><li>We received the feed that the friends system is not convenient enough. Most players already have a long friends list on their gaming platform, like steam, origin and uplay. We can connect our account to those platforms, therefore making easy for players to find the friend. We can also add a group function so a group of players can find each other inside their own community very conveniently.</li></ul></li></ul><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3qxftdusWUE" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>The point of view that we came up to is “people should have a way of acquiring game info more efficiently and accurately” What we want to achieve is to use an app to enhance the experiences of playing complex and intense games. For example, when people are playing intense shooting games, it is difficult to communicate with teammates and get accurate information without affect their controls. By using the app we develop, they can deal with these tricky problems. Our inspiration comes from our observation of different people playing games, and also the experiences of ourselves playing games. By carefully observing the gaming processes, we come up with many ideas of improving the experiences, like adding label function for users to communicate with each other with just several clicks. Also we get some inspiration from some games which deal with the problems we found in good ways, like PUBG. Adding mark on the map is the idea that we found on PUBG since we found it is very efficient for users to communicate. Overall, we are still in the process of developing our app by following our point of view.  </p><h3 id="COMPARATIVE-EVALUATION"><a href="#COMPARATIVE-EVALUATION" class="headerlink" title="COMPARATIVE EVALUATION"></a>COMPARATIVE EVALUATION</h3><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/uJPL5VG.png"><br>During our comparative evaluation, we mainly tested three aspects related to our change in home page. We counted how long people would stay on the homepage for the first time because an obvious problem of our first prototype is its lack of guidance so this data could show us how well we did in improving the overall accessibility if testers were able to directly figure out the logic flow of the app. Secondly, we recorded the number of clicks for current game since the icon we had used in our first prototype was very inconspicuous so we would like to see the difference between our redesigned page and the original one. Besides, we also recorded the clicking frequency of account buttons in navigation bar in that we made it look more distinguishable from other elements and thus we expected more clicks on it. Previously we had to directly tell testers the ‘account’ button was actually clickable.<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/yuAg5rX.png"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Po5tgAy.png"><br>We have many meaningful findings on our comparative evaluation results. We focus on three major aspects of our changes, including time people stay on the homepage, number of clicks for current game and number of clicks for account. According to the results, we found out that there are obvious increase of click times for current game buttons and account buttons on navigation. For the original page, the click times for current game button range from 0 - 3, and click times for account button range from 0-2. Both these two data shows our designs for these two parts are not clear. And we found many users did not notice that there is a current game button on the bottom. What’s more, some users asked us what current button for. This shows that they are confused about these two buttons. For the redesign page, we found an increase of click times for these two buttons. Especially the current game button. We have a max number of 6 click times. This shows that our redesign make these two button more noticeable to users. However, there are also some changes we need to reconsider. For example, the background design for the homepage. We found out that users spend more time stare at our redesign homepage than our original homepage. This shows that users are more confused about our redesign page. And we also heard users complained about the redesign pages. They think this page is a little bit redundant. So we should definitely need to redesign this page. Furthermore, we should add more content on account page and reflect the change of different settings.</p><p>In conclusion, our redesign make significant improvement on user experiences. Especially for the current game button and account navigation. However, we still need to think about how to make our homepage clear and clean. So that users do not feel redundant.</p><p>P.S. The way we recorded the data of clicking frequencies was to let testers go back and forth between our core function page and home page about 6~7 rounds, which allowed us to observe how many times if they click a button or not.</p><h3 id="FUTURE-IMPROVEMENT"><a href="#FUTURE-IMPROVEMENT" class="headerlink" title="FUTURE IMPROVEMENT"></a>FUTURE IMPROVEMENT</h3><ol><li><p>We should make the design for home page cleaner, since some users complained about the redundancy of this page.</p></li><li><p>We can redesign the logic of create a room. Maybe delete the “using default name option”, or reorganized the create name processes.</p></li><li><p>We should add more functions on the account page such as game customization and friend list so that users can see the reflection of changes.</p></li><li><p>We should add a invitation function which allows the hosts to add their friends directly for time saving purpose.</p></li><li><p>We should have a lightweight homepage that removes the options players usually don’t need at the moment. For example, if the player is already in a room, he may not need “create a new room” option and this can be hid until he finds a new room.</p></li><li><p>Maybe we should have larger buttons for certain map functions, such as next floor and prev floor, since players need to quickly tap them during gaming.</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>front-end</tag>
      
      <tag>UI/UX</tag>
      
      <tag>e-sports</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Troop on Mars</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Troop-on-Mars/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Troop-on-Mars/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Take It Home 2.0 remote control car that take you experience the Mars exploration.</em></p><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GbGx33DISvY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Playing with toys is one of the most common daily activities of children. Toddlers can improve their practical abilities and imagination through playing different kind of toys. However, our group realize that designing a toy is much more difficult than simply playing a toy because toy designers need to think over various aspects of a toy but not to rely on their intuitions in production. Specifically, a good toy should not only provide children enough interactivity but also possibility of collaboration. These characteristics are the radical sources that bring fun to children. The way of interaction ought to be very concise and intuitive for children so that they are able to understand some basic rules from randomly operating the system like pressing buttons in their own way by curiosity. “All the toys one commonly sees are essentially a microcosm of the adult world” (Jenks, 142). </p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/c0dRaxf.jpg"></p><p>As a result, children will gradually become more and more familiar with the logic behind and finally master a new approach of interacting with the world. Besides, if a toy allows children to cooperate with each other, it can rapidly develop their communication skills during childhood, which enables children to talk spontaneously thus they will prefer to share their thoughts with their surroundings rather than keep silence. As Etienne Benson describes in his work, “Toys are opportunities for play, for exploration, and for social interaction; an educational toy that promotes these will have a positive effect, but so will an everyday household object — if used in the right way.” Therefore, our group decides to create a new type of remote control car which satisfies those criterions as far as possible, which leads to the starting point of our project.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/5IvhDtP.jpg"></p><p>To integrate such innovative experience for young players, we separate the whole remote-control section into two different parts, in other words, a navigator and a controller. The former is able to use his phone to view the frame transmitted by the camera on the car while the latter can only blindly control the car’s movement following the instruction of the navigator. We expect children to experience different characters to distinguish both advantages and disadvantages of those two characters instead of particularly concentrating on single player experience. Hence, they can learn from their experiences and then guide the other player effectively after numbers of trial. Consequently, we find out that our game should be challenging enough in order that collaboration will become player’s first choice. For that reason, NASA’s remotely Control Planetary Rover and Djedi robot inspires us a lot in our project. They both use multiple sensors and camera to explore unknown area around the world, which grants user to observe an area from different angle through the camera. It is difficult for a child to operate such robot on his own. Nonetheless, the appearances of those robots are too mechanical to be attractive to children so we creatively add a screen to show the emotion status of our car. It can constantly change along with the car’s behavior so that it will trigger children’s thirst of probing how many facial expressions the car could have. </p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/sAZibmD.jpg"> </p><p>Accordingly, the context of our game is set on Mars. Players can imagine that they are controlling a space exploration Rover from Earth to find human being’s temporary base on that red planet. Because of “some loss in data transmission”, players can easily perceive the lag existing in both frame transmission and inputting commands. Namely, it requires a certain level of cooperation between the navigator and the controller to clear the game. So, during the game, it might spend both sides a lot of time and energy on determining the subtle balance. Although it is totally possible for them to complain about each other, they are actually communicating and solving the problem together. As Luisa Magalhaes and Jeffrey Goldstein states in their book, “The specificity of the toys, and beyond that of games, is to provide fun education, associated with entertainment, or at the very least to display this in the discourse accompanying the toy and in the toy itself, as we have seen” (44). This is the key concept that continuously affects our project. By alternately acting as navigator and controller, players will slowly get accustomed to the mechanism of the game and become more patient to other’s fault as they also understand what they are suffering. Thus, they will rather encourage their teammates and help them out of trouble, which is exactly a successful team should look like.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/l97dRYu.jpg"> </p><p>For the sake of user friendly interface and lightweight design, we use Raspberry Pi 3 as the motherboard but not Arduino because Arduino’s CPU is not powerful enough to handle massive calculation and does not support Real-time task well assigned by users. In addition, Raspberry Pi already provides all kinds of ports including GPIO, USB and other popular interfaces so it is relatively more convenient to use Raspberry Pi especially when we are not capable of setting up our complex circuit with Arduino. As a consequence, we just need to write Python program to drive the motor and screen because they are both connected to the GPIO side of Raspberry Pi. The other components such as chassis and wheels are all made of plastics as this kind of material is safe for children and can remarkably reduce the total weight of the car. Moreover, since Raspberry Pi has wireless module, we can directly transfer the video data from camera to navigator’s cellphone as a portable monitor through wireless networks. On the other hand, controllers can use either keyboard or DualShock 4 controller to control the car. Their mission is to drive the car back to its base under efficient collaboration between players. </p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/70DdSqW.jpg"></p><p>What’s more, due to the high customizability of the screen, users can display whatever they want on that LED screen. That is to say, the screen not only simulates the way how scientist communicate with extraneous creatures but in real life also enables child to interact with the world in a different way. For example, during the game, if the navigator accidentally sees his parents on his phone, he can ask his partner to show some greetings on the screen. Clearly such feature can imperceptibly promote family relationships and friendships, which makes the car more than a toy but a communication tool which connects everyone together into one place. Like Rodney P. Carlisle says, “Many scripts come from children’s own observations of adult life, and fantasy play has often been considered direct preparation for adult roles” (225). In other words, children are willing to sharing their perspectives because their subconsciousness know they should practice such skills. The screen on the car provides them a platform to talk with other people by using not only texts but also emoji to express themselves, which makes them well prepared for their adulthood.</p><p>We once worried about whether children will like our project or not because it is essentially still a remote-control car. Youngster nowadays may prefer to play with electronic devices like iPad rather than such classic toy in our generation. Fortunately, we receive many positive feedbacks from those young visitors. They begin to communicate with their partners to find the best solution as soon as they understand the responsibility of their corresponding characters. It looks like a moveable car is appealing for children as usual. Not to mention the sense of achievement they can earn after overcoming the difficulties they have met during the game. Nevertheless, we also find some shortages in our project through observing their playing progress. Firstly, our remote-control car does not have excellent handling. We notice that even a pair of player know exactly what they are going to do next, the car will not respond to their command in the same way as they may have expected. Such kind of imperfection might significantly frustrate players. In consequence, we will add a switch that allows player to modify the sensitiveness of the handling. Secondly, if there is only tiny space for playing, we would like to include an extra opaque cover in the container as we want to make sure that controller is not able to directly see the car otherwise it will ruin the whole game experience of both side. Besides, we decide to do more research on the camera to check if it can support night vision so our toy could be played at any time anywhere.</p><p>In conclusion, through making a toy by ourselves, we have understood the basic ideas about how to create an interactive product for specific age group. Balancing the boundary between interesting and educating purposes requires us to make a detailed plan before we make the prototype. Furthermore, we can rely on the feedbacks from our target audiences even in the middle of our production to define a goal for our next iteration. In a nutshell, evaluating our own project undoubtedly makes us know the development process and we can implement such valuable experiences into our future works.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/5eQQf1Q.jpg"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>hardware engineering</tag>
      
      <tag>Arduino</tag>
      
      <tag>Python</tag>
      
      <tag>Raspberry Pi</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Job Board based on React</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Job-Board-based-on-React/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Job-Board-based-on-React/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>###<a href="https://sizhao-jobboard.herokuapp.com/">Click here to visit!</a></p><h3 id="Brief"><a href="#Brief" class="headerlink" title="Brief"></a>Brief</h3><p>Job Board is a full-stack project based on ReactJS and MongoDB. It supports basic user authentication and authorization by Oauth and react-router. The project also uses redux to manage the states of user and data retrieved from api. For the back-end of the project, I use Express.js as middleware to handle communications between front-end request and database, which also enables me to write RESTful API for readability.</p><p>A main difference between Vue and React I found in developing this project is that Vue provides a lot of pre-defined render methods while React relies heavily on JSX though it provides more freedom during programming. Of course, which framework to use depends on the scenario instead of syntax. </p><p><strong>Screen Shots:</strong></p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/CyBgJCY.jpg"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>react</tag>
      
      <tag>front-end</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Photography</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Photography/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Photography/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Some-photos-I-randomly-took-in-traveling"><a href="#Some-photos-I-randomly-took-in-traveling" class="headerlink" title="Some photos I randomly took in traveling."></a>Some photos I randomly took in traveling.</h2><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/GIeJkpC.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/vfs6oCJ.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/cvd5sUY.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/nrADxJh.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/wGvndt0.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/V9Jvf4I.jpg"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/K6vLqAO.png"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/EW6udKc.jpg"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>photography</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>photos</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mini Game Project</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Mini-Game-Project/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Mini-Game-Project/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Intro-Campus-Simulator"><a href="#Intro-Campus-Simulator" class="headerlink" title="Intro - Campus Simulator"></a>Intro - Campus Simulator</h3><p>Campus simulator is a python based game that allows player to experience the daily struggles college student may encounter during their campus life. Resist the desire of being lazy and defeat Exam like what players have done in classic RPG game. </p><p>The Goal of this project is to practice python syntax and logic while testing the possibility of PyGame Library. I spent some time before programming to determine how to build all the classes I needed as following</p><ol><li>Player </li><li>game_status</li><li>Monster</li><li>Stage1<ul><li>stage misc</li></ul></li><li>Stage2<ul><li>stage misc</li></ul></li><li>Stage3  <ul><li>stage misc</li></ul></li></ol><p>so that I did not need to worry about extensibility later. Furthermore, I also used Sprite in PyGame to add dynamic performance of the game, which made me to consider the frame rate and x &amp; y coordinate relationship among each frames. </p><p><a href="https://github.com/SplashCrBy/campus_simulator">Github Link</a></p><iframe width="583" height="438" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uIir5vN-6Y0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>  <h3 id="Intro-Checker-Mini-Game"><a href="#Intro-Checker-Mini-Game" class="headerlink" title="Intro - Checker Mini Game"></a>Intro - Checker Mini Game</h3><p>Checker is a python based board game that allows player to play with second player or AI. The challenges of this project include paraphrasing the game rules into actual codes and disseminate classes into their smallest granularity. </p><p>The goal of this project is to practice both top-down and bottom-up approach in programming. I learned about how to update the whole stage from a single move.</p><p>A main takeaway is that good structure design really helps developer solving edge cases and potential bugs during developing. How to locate common properties among different objects in initial approach is very important to write robust code.  </p><p><a href="https://github.com/SplashCrBy/Checker">Github Link</a></p><p><strong>Screen Shots:</strong> </p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/wPDwsRn.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>python</tag>
      
      <tag>pygame</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Project Numinous</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Project-Numinous/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Project-Numinous/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>ULTIMATE CONCERN FOR ELDERS.</em></p><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nclk470eVc4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><h3 id="THE-BACKGROUND-OF-OUR-TEAM"><a href="#THE-BACKGROUND-OF-OUR-TEAM" class="headerlink" title="THE BACKGROUND OF OUR TEAM"></a>THE BACKGROUND OF OUR TEAM</h3><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/cBH1cnX.jpg"><br>The team Numinous consisted of totally 6 students who were interested in UI&#x2F;UX design and programming. Their goal was to solve the loneliness problem encountering by many elders so they decided to develop an App together to help those elders step out from such dilemma. The logo was designed by Sizhao Li and adopted by the whole team as we believed it expressed the feeling of Numinous through creatively synthesising different elements including ocelot, moon and mystique.</p><p>My Role: Chief UI&#x2F;UX design</p><p>Team member: Sizhao Li, Juan Zapien, Hanhui Lou, Zhaoyue Xiang, Peter Chen, Yaohui Lu</p><p>Tools: Photoshop, illustrator</p><h3 id="PROBLEM"><a href="#PROBLEM" class="headerlink" title="PROBLEM"></a>PROBLEM</h3><p>After a series of discussion, we found out that many elders were suffering from loneliness because their children were very busy so that the elders did not want to occupy their time. Therefore, they could only kill time by themselves. Furthermore, some researches also showed that 43 percent of elderly people over 60 years old had feelings of loneliness. Besides, children may did not know what were the needs of their parents so they would just prefer maintaining the status quo instead of making some changes.  Hence, they needed an App which could help them to reunite together.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/XmPRq1o.jpg"></p><h3 id="WHAT-WE-DID"><a href="#WHAT-WE-DID" class="headerlink" title="WHAT WE DID"></a>WHAT WE DID</h3><p>We developed an App called “Gather” for not only elders but also for all family members. They were able to arrange events and view their family trees conveniently. The video shows the rough concept of our App. </p><iframe width="100%" height="540px" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B5Bj0zDjh6Q" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><h3 id="WORKFLOW-OF-OUR-APP-DEVELOPMENT"><a href="#WORKFLOW-OF-OUR-APP-DEVELOPMENT" class="headerlink" title="WORKFLOW OF OUR APP DEVELOPMENT"></a>WORKFLOW OF OUR APP DEVELOPMENT</h3><p><strong>STORYBOARD &amp; PERSONAS</strong></p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/XmPRq1o.jpg"></p><p>According to the survey result we did with our own family members and local nursing house, we drew several storyboards and personas to embody our ideas about how to solve such problem. We also tried different approaches to solve the problem but we finally decided to focus on mobile device because it was the most popular tools among all kinds of generations. In conclusion, we learned more about our users than we expected by sketching user experiences, but we still have a lot to iterate and think before making the actual product.  </p><p><strong>COMPETITIVE ANALYSIS</strong><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/PsrtX8n.png"></p><p><strong>PROTOTYPING</strong><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ntr36d2.png"><br>The clumsiness of our first draft soon drew our attention since there were so many texts over the layouts, which was not friendly to senior users. As a result, we decided to optimize the usability of the App. Specifically, we tried our best to diminish the existence of texts in our App and replaced them with icons or hand gestures to make it more accessible. Furthermore, in order to encourage the participation of family groups, we created a real tree-like family tree to trace the relationship between each pair of family members. Users could improve the health level of the tree through participating in different family activities. They could also share the photos of each activities and comment on them for memorizing purpose. </p><p><strong>USER TESTING &amp; FEEDBACK</strong><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/PzVCLVX.jpg"><br>We all understood that the decisions we made during this time would be critical to our success in making an app that was suitable to the needs of the elderly. With that in mind, we needed to take the next step and acquire feedback from the users, in this case being the other students in the class.<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/2NmDx20.jpg"><br>The importance of user feedback is a critical component to the overall process of creating a meaningful product. Feedback provides valuable insight on design flaws, and these opinions from an outside perspective widen our ability to think of new ideas to make improvements to our app. After prototyping our app, it was necessary to take a step back and revisit the creative stage making use of the feedback given to us.</p><h3 id="Final-Product"><a href="#Final-Product" class="headerlink" title="Final Product"></a>Final Product</h3><p>We chose our main color as green, because most of our team members love the color green. Also, green represents health and we hoped our app will bring both physical and emotional health to the senior people as well as their family members.  For our home page, there are basically four functions: Calendar to schedule the meeting, Memories to view the past events, Tree to add family members and Settings to set the custom options.  </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>UI/UX</tag>
      
      <tag>design</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Project MindWave</title>
    <link href="/2022/02/14/Project-MindWave/"/>
    <url>/2022/02/14/Project-MindWave/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Is art making a mysterious process which requires extensive training and inspiration? My answer is no. People innately have the ability to create things on their own thought.</em></p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ChaLDAe.png"></p><p>The goal of this installation is to make the art-making process simpler so that everyone can participate in creating their own art pieces. My idea is triggered by the “disenchantment” brought up by Max Weber. Specifically, the term emphasizes the ability of human beings and reduces the importance of mysterious power including god, karma. Therefore, a key element in my project is players’ bodies because they are the embodied representation of their inner thought, in other words, brainwaves. As a consequence, the brain computer interface naturally comes into my mind as it can accurately reflect the fluctuation of people’s mind. I finally decide to use EEG instead of FMRI and MEG because it has better temporal resolution and its portability is compatible with the needs of installation art. Nevertheless, how to transform the brainwave into tangible elements that can be appreciated by the audiences? After a period of research, I find that they combine both music and visual stuff to reflect the change of their mind status. The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IctphI0mTHI">MIDI distortion with EEG</a> and the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1sXL3SAELoc">magical wall</a> are good references while they lack of either the participation of interactive elements or spontaneous creation in their projects.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/E0ABFlV.jpg"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/XS6fFye.jpg"><br>Consequently, I then determine to add an interactive part into my project to make the process much more engaging. The form I take is a rhythm game because it can integrate both music and visual elements well. Since the EEG requires extensive training to allow audience to produce the exact note as their imagination (the computer will play C1 if audiences think C1 in their mind), my first approach is to generate notes based on the variation of brainwave, but the demo showed in final presentation already proves that this way does not match the primary expectation. Hence, adding sound effect on a completed music piece should be an ideal substitution because the whole gaming process is much more consistent and melodious. Furthermore, external input should be given to audiences instead of letting them use keyboard because it is more intuitive and interesting to play as a real DJ and real DJ does not spin discs with keyboards. In the example of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JvIRIUHJfp0">PERISCOPISTA</a> we could see that audiences are able to use body gestures and voice to interact, which became an inspiration of my approach. Visual elements are also important in this project because they are the visualization of the music and trigger audience to explore more on this project (to try different visual effects).<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/jiGi1fO.png"><br>During implementation stage, since most of the work relate to coding, it spends me a lot of time on realizing the game since I never program a rhythm game before, so I search the document of Processing to see what I can do with it. After the game is playable, I take another 2 hours to determine the algorithm that differentiates the EEG signals as far as possible since the readings are really close. In short, I use the remainder of a series computation to determine their (notes) directions. The connection quality of EEG headset is also unstable so that I specific a web socket for it and it then works well. But for now, the focus is moved to sound aspects, so it may take me several times to figure out how to realize sound alternation in Processing. I also Makey-Makey instead of Arduino because the former is much easier to use. Thus, the further criteria of my project are to measure if the mixing sound effect is harmonious considering the visual performance and whether the external controller is attractive and related to the theme of music remixing. To put it in another way, using instrument-like controller is expected in the future implementation.<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/UuxYf56.png"><br>The thing totally has three different phases, red, yellow and green, which reflects different mental status from high to low. The signals read by processing will then trigger midi notes in ableton that help audiences to determine their mental status. Furthermore, they are able to create their own music in this way because of the high variety of brainwaves. Users are also allowed to use keyboard to control the sound output as a type of remix.<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Won5r14.png"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ZmZSbbG.png"><br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/JM2zBfn.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>python</tag>
      
      <tag>EEG</tag>
      
      <tag>Human Computer Interface</tag>
      
      <tag>Processing</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
